<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Taiwanese Citizenship</title>
    <link>https://citizen.tw/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Taiwanese Citizenship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://citizen.tw/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Disclaimer and Terms of Use</title>
      <link>https://citizen.tw/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://citizen.tw/terms/</guid>
      <description>Taiwan Citizenship is a community website maintained by the community. We are not affiliated, associated, authorized, endorsed by, or in any way officially connected with any governments, its departments or agencies. Official information can be found on the official websites.
The information herein is for general informational purpose only. We make no representation or warranty of any kind, express or implied, regarding the accuracy, adequacy, validity, reliability, availability or completeness of any information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Level Professional</title>
      <link>https://citizen.tw/high-level-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://citizen.tw/high-level-professional/</guid>
      <description>Process Overview The process for Taiwanese citizenship application as a High-Level professional is at first glance, painfully simple:
 Apply to your favourite (central) government ministry for a letter of recommendation that acknowledges you as a High-Level Professional fit for naturalisation Apply for naturalisation as a High-Level Professional at your local Household Registration Office.  It is, of course, much more difficult in practice.
The official instructions are available in English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outstanding Contributions</title>
      <link>https://citizen.tw/outstanding-contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://citizen.tw/outstanding-contributions/</guid>
      <description>Qualification Application for citizenship through Outstanding Contributions to Taiwan are very rare. Generally, the applicants have spent decades making significant and selfless efforts towards improving one or more aspects of Taiwan. If you&amp;rsquo;re finding this out from this website rather than talking to your friends in the government, you&amp;rsquo;re probably not qualified ;)
However, in theory, there is a standardized process and set of requirements. If you meet any of the following, you must ask the government agency or organisation responsible to provide certifying documents and a letter of recommendation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regular Application</title>
      <link>https://citizen.tw/regular-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://citizen.tw/regular-application/</guid>
      <description>Process Overview Application for citizenship is submitted at your local Household Registration Office. You will first need to meet the residence requirement, prove your language ability, clean criminal record and proof of funds. With this you will be able to initiate the citizenship applicaiton process and if successful will be issued a Certificate of R.O.C. Naturalization Candidature.
You then have one year to renounce your original citizenship and provide certified and formal proof of this (or certified and formal proof it is impossible) to the Household Registration Office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relevant Laws</title>
      <link>https://citizen.tw/relevant-laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://citizen.tw/relevant-laws/</guid>
      <description>Nationality Act https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?PCode=D0030001
Enforcement Rules of the Nationality Act https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?PCode=D0030022
Standards for Identification of Basic Language Abilities and General Knowledge of the Rights and Duties of Naturalized R.O.C. Citizens https://law.moj.gov.tw/ENG/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=D0030028
Directions for Identifying a Foreign National or a Stateless Person Who Has Made Special Contributions to the ROC https://www.ris.gov.tw/documents/data/en/2/Directions-for-Identifying-a-Foreign-National-or-a-Stateless-Person-Who-has-Made-Special-Contributions-to-the-ROC.pdf
Standards for Defining High-Level Professionals for Naturalization https://www.ris.gov.tw/documents/data/en/2/Standards-for-Defining-High-Level-Professionals-for-Naturalization.pdf
Orders Act https://law.moj.gov.tw/ENG/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=A0030006</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taiwanese Parents</title>
      <link>https://citizen.tw/taiwanese-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://citizen.tw/taiwanese-parents/</guid>
      <description>Introduction There is an important conceptual difference in Taiwanese citizenship compared to that of other countries. Essentially, Taiwan only has the concept of a &amp;ldquo;national&amp;rdquo;, and what most of us think of as the rights of a citizen are tied with what is known as &amp;ldquo;Household Registration&amp;rdquo;. Nationals with full residence and voting rights are known as &amp;ldquo;Nationals with Household Registration&amp;rdquo;.
There are many Taiwanese nationals living overseas, who may be unaware they are Taiwanese, because they do not have the right to live or work in Taiwan without taking some additional steps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>